can you tell me how to get rid of this
stupid
bar what whatever you can get rid
of like minimize yeah yeah just need all
these things minimized I think it's a
it's a minimum that you can get okay
this is what it is okay fine you can do
it
more let me
try W thank you so much um this
[Music]
one
information I I I don't want to know
this I always ask someone to help me
yeah yeah okay okay let's get started uh
okay so today this is lecture five 5A
and uh uh this is going to be on uh on
essentially stuff from classical
robotics that everybody should know okay
and uh I'm going to divide this up into
three segments uh robot Dynamics control
and motion planning so people who have
taken a full-fledged classical robotics
class should know all this uh others may
not but uh I think that I need to do a
review to bring everybody up to the same
place okay so
uh okay so the three topics are robot
Dynamics robot control robot motion
planning very straightforward okay let's
start with Dynamics so first of all uh
going back some lectures ago maybe in
the second lecture
we talked about robot kinematics so this
is essentially about the geometry of the
system so you have a frame at the base
of the robot or somewhere in the room
which is called the S frame and then
there is a b frame which is the body
frame which is somewhere on the robot
and uh what we know is the geometry so
we know the lengths of every link and uh
we have joint angles and with this we
can calculate
the configuration at for example the end
effector and uh uh the the the solution
was that it is essentially a series of
exponentials exponentials of screws uh
that we compose them together and that's
how we get the final configuration and
again we did the the big story uh last
time
so uh the product of exponentials uh is
a nice elegant way of stating this it is
derived from what are called Le groups
and Le Theory uh but there is a simple
version of it which is just for
rotations which is exponentials of skew
symmetric
matrices represent rotations and then
you can compose them and there's a
generalization where both rotations and
translations are being considered and
that's where you need to consider the
so-called screw
motion okay uh how do we make all this
practical this is made practical through
the urdf so we describe every robot
using this urdf and the robot
manufacturer is supposed to supply to
you the urdf so if you look on the lower
left that's a kinematics what is it
telling you you can read it uh name
joint two type revolute so therefore
that's a revolute joint there's a parent
link a parent Child Link origin axis
length so this is basically telling you
about the geometry like how long are the
links and so forth right and then if
there are joint limits in terms of what
angles can be achieved or not achieved
okay there's a second part on the right
which is called the link element and it
refers to inertial properties so inertia
here as in inertia of movement so
basically we're talking about physics f
equals ma torque equals I * Omega that's
what is involved here and if you notice
the what's being described there Mass so
we probably the mass of the robot Link
in kilograms or whatever then there is
the inertia which is in iixx iix y so
these are different axes about which you
compute the moments of inertia so uh all
of that is specified and this is the
physics of the robot so we we specified
the geometry of the robot and the
physics of the robot and this URF format
and then what we have to do is to figure
out the Dynamics Dynamics here refers to
forces and torqus and movement in
various ways and there is uh uh there
are two problems here one is What's
called the forward Dynamics problem so
the forward Dynamics problem is that you
are given
uh Theta Theta here is a vector this
corresponds to all the joint angles
there's Theta dot which is how are all
the joint angles changing there's to to
here is a vector corresponding to the
torqus applied at every joint so
basically you have some electric motors
which are which are applying torqus at
every joint so this is the input and
then the output is Theta double dot
which is how the joint angles
accelerating because physics is about
acceleration f equals ma a means
acceleration right so that's the forward
Dynamics problem we are in a certain
configuration we apply some forces or
talks what will happen next what will be
the acceleration and then you can kind
of integrate from that right so that you
you have a short Moment In Time delta T
you figure out the new configuration you
continue so that's a forward problem
there is the inverse Dynamics problem so
the inverse Dynamics problem is that uh
what do you control you control all your
electric motors which are rotating all
the joints so that's the tow right tow
here is a vector of torqus so that's
what you want to control and what's the
input input is whatever you want in
terms of desired configuration desired
rate of change of configuration and so
on so the input is Theta Theta dot Theta
double
dot so this is uh very well defined
problem uh and essentially nice ways of
solving it were worked out back in the'
70s and 80s and 90s so it's all there's
a solve problem you don't need to worry
about it it's all worked out it's there
in the libraries but I'm going to give
you the the five minute version so that
you have some intuition of what's going
on underneath the hood and again for
Dynamics uh there are classic ways of
doing it I mean f equals ma the Newton
method which you can integrate in time
this is what you learned in high school
or whatever freshman physics or whatever
and then there's a fancier way which is
the legran Dynamics the difference
between them is essentially when you
have multiple degrees of freedom and the
motion is constrained in some way then
the lren formulation is more convenient
because it's in terms of the true
degrees of freedom of the
system
uh okay so I'm going to uh do like this
very cartoon version of this so that you
have a feeling of what it's about and
don't expect to really understand this
properly to understand this properly you
should take uh 106a which is the class
shanka shastri teaches so that's the
answer so but I want to you to I I I
feel that there's nothing you should
learn as a blackbox you should have some
intuition so I want to give you some
intuition so this is a simple twool link
robot uh you you have this first link uh
and then uh and then there is uh this uh
this thing which is connected to it so
there's this Mass M1 is the first link
and mass M2 is the second link and then
uh and then you can rotate the first
link so that has a revolute joint at the
base here okay and then the second joint
is a prismatic joint so you can move it
translate it okay so it's a you don't
want actually use this robot this is a
very simple robot to just illustrate
concept
so what you're supposed to do in the
legran formulation is that you're
supposed to figure out the potential
energy and the kinetic energy and take
the difference of the two so the kinetic
energy minus the potential energy and
this is sometimes called the
action
yeah okay and now uh so what is the what
are the so again the to give the flavors
of the terms the first term so what's
the first term M1 G y1 so this is
potential energy so it's basically your
MGH H right mass times the acceleration
due to gravity times the height that's
what again you're supposed to have
learned this in high school okay so now
that height here is is in the wide so
there's a XY coordinate system and the Y
is the height so you calculate the the
height and it's going to be L1 time the
S of theta 1 okay uh similarly for the
second joint what's the kinetic energy k
IC energy is basically half mv^ s right
so you have to figure out what is the
velocity which for the first joint is
going to be in terms of X1 do^ s + y1
do^ S and then there is this second term
which has to do with this this uh this
in rotational inertia so moment of
inertia I and then Theta 1 dot which is
the angular velocity okay I'm I'm I've
just waved this in front of you and I'm
not going to continue in detail the rest
of the calculation but if you are
curious I've got this reference on the
slide which is uh find men lectures when
I was a kid I I read this chapter on the
principle of leas traction it is one of
the most beautiful expositions of this
principle uh which is underlying lren
mechanics okay but you can find it in
finan lectures and you can actually find
this lecture on YouTube I mean I had to
read it from a book anyway
so okay uh and then blah blah blah so
okay now uh you do a lot of algebra and
at the end you get this equation which
is at the top so I think we can look at
the abstracted form of this equation so
let's just understand what the terms are
to to is a vector so this corresponds to
the torqus applied at each of the joints
so if you have two joint so there might
be two of these right uh uh what is M of
theta M of theta is some Matrix
the m is supposed to tell you that it's
about masses so it's the mass in some
form right it's the inertia part what is
Theta double dot well that's the second
order
centripedal forces and corus forces and
so that's indicated in the second column
vector and then there is this G of theta
the G here stands for Gravity so this is
the gravitational part so you can see
the terms G showing up in each of these
again
don't the derivation here is following
standard stuff which any physicist in
1800 could derive right he would not
have used Vector Matrix notation but
it's it's basically that okay so we can
work all this out and uh okay uh but now
let's just uh so let's now just act like
computer scientists we've got an
abstraction on top so the abstraction on
top is that there is this kind of an
equation which you can write down in
four different forms but it's the same
equation so one is the torque equals m m
these are matrices and vectors just
remember that plus this H this H is uh
can be split into two terms one part
which is kind of this velocity product
terms one part which is due to gravity
then this can be written in another
other ways blah blah blah okay it's just
these that different formats in which we
write down the basic physics of the
situation and then there is this term
this last term which is somewhat
interesting and now relevant for
robotics there is this Jacobian
transpose of theta
time F tip what is that so if you are
trying to apply a force at the tip of
the robot so this you might want to do
right suppose you what you're trying to
do is with your robot tip you're trying
to apply some Force to the wall or
you're trying to uh screw something in
or push something you're applying a
force right so there's an external force
that you want to be output from the
system so so that's that term and it
then the Jacobian is going to do the
appropriate transformation in the system
so the intuition is quite easy and clear
and the mumbo jumbo can be worked out by
by other people or by some computer
algebra
system okay next uh so now uh so that's
my topic one so you can spend a few
weeks and understand this properly or
you can just take it that at the end
you'll get a system of equations of this
type trust me okay the second second
part of this lecture is about
control and uh because we are now
getting into the game that we need to uh
we need to do something so we are going
to apply some TS at the joints with the
goal of achieving a certain movement of
the end tip of the robot or some
application of forces or both and I'm
going to give you examples where for
different manipulation tasks you need to
either apply uh a do uh move movement
control or uh Force control let's give
one easy example suppose you want to uh
uh write on the board then the the
marker that you're using the tip of the
marker needs to move on a certain
trajectory so that's movement control
but then there is a force which you
apply into the Whiteboard which you
don't want you want to be a little bit
but not too much right so that's the
force control so once you have force and
movement control then it's called hybrid
control because you're controlling both
so we want to understand
control now
uh uh this come now there is a Schism
based on whether you're an e undergrad
or CS undergrad so every e undergrad
should have taken a class on control
okay very likely every CS undergrad has
not taken a class on control okay and
the way you encounter control is
probably through reinforcement learning
and reinforcement learning is very fancy
mumbo jumbo in principle you should
never learn reinforcement learning
without having studied control first but
sadly that's not the way the educational
system works so it is my duty to make up
for this Gap in your education okay can
I just take a poll by the way how many
people in this room have have have not
taken a control
class okay so it
I think it's like uh maybe one quarter
one3 so it justifies me teaching it even
for the people who have done control you
might I'm hoping you have forgotten
enough of it that this class offers some
value so I've got this super baby
example but this is essential to
understand with this you can understand
the intuition of control so the problem
we're going to study is like this very
tiny easy problem but it illustrates
what control is about so the problem is
that of driving your car and cruise
control so what we are doing is we are
driving a car and this is an
oldfashioned car there are no computers
involved it's like you pressing on the
the accelerator so this is a called the
throttle so there's an angle and every
time you press down by one degree the
speed of the car goes up in some way
okay so that's a your so the control so
the controller here is like the human or
it could be some computer program
what's the control variable the throttle
so the throttle is this how much you
press down on the accelerator so the
angle okay and then there is an actuator
actuator is the terminology in this case
it stands for the engine right the
internal combustion engine your electric
motor whatever okay and then there is
this the auto body I mean the 2000 pound
Mass which is your
car and then this is affected by
uh by the road surface which let's say
you don't know the road could be flat
the road could be sloping up the road
could be sloping down right and you
don't know exactly what it is but it's
going to exert some disturbance on the
system okay and then as a result you'll
get an actual speed for a certain
setting of the of the
accelerator right and then of course you
have a speedometer so you can measure
the speed so this is a very simple
scenario
so but this is more interesting I mean
when control is introduced the first
example is that of a thermostat but this
should be the second example so I'm
taking just the second example okay so
now let's convert it into math and the
mathematical model is shown here so
there is some control which is in
degrees so degrees of angle on your
accelerator then there is uh some output
speed and our simple model here is a one
degree change in throttle angle causes
your speed to go up by 10
mph simple just a model and then uh and
then you have the effect of the unknown
environment and the effect of the unv
unknown environment is that the slope of
the of the road surface so if 1% change
in grade causes a speed change by 5 mil
per hour so if you are going uphill at a
slope of 1° your speed will be reduced
by 5 amp you're going downhill it'll go
up by 5 m okay so there are grow
simplifications about the Dynamics here
which is fine this is just a simple
model okay so far so good okay now how
do we control this this uh
car okay so what uh the the simpleminded
way is uh what open loop control or feed
forward control so uh what would you do
you so you have this variable R which is
you get to control the thing here
right so what you do is you want a
certain speed so you just press the
accelerator by that amount right okay so
you you get uh uh you you you y equals
so the variables here are U is the
control that's a standard ter symbol
used for control it goes back I believe
to maybe Al knows this the word control
in Russian begins with a something with
a
u have you I have no idea okay so anyway
I that's what I somebody told me but I
need to verify this okay so uh uh okay
so you you can work out the the uh so
and then there is so so the open loop
approach which is that you press the
accelerator by the amount that you need
to in order to get the right speed that
model will do the right
thing except for the fact that there is
this disturbance which is the fact that
the road that you're going on is has
some slope and we've got a little model
here of that phenomenon which is that
the there is a so so essentially there's
this this the the effect of uh so this
why
y = 10 of u -.5 w okay so this is
essentially saying the effect of the
accelerator which is the control U and
then there is the effect of the slope
right and uh and then you uh and then
this is this this point
one R is what we worked out because we
because we have this this rule that we
had here sorry there's one degree change
causes speed change by 10 m hour so
because of that we did that uh we did do
do this 0.1
thing okay uh minus5 W and then if you
uh work this out it comes out to be R
minus 5 W okay so let me explain all of
this Y is the actual
speed R is the reference speed so this
is a standard terminology from control
so the reference speed might be your 50
m hour whatever right so by so the and
then minus 5w so what this is saying is
that in open loop
control if the there is no disturbance
there's no noise there is no Road slope
it's flat then the effect of this this
5w is
zero and Y is equal to R so that means
that the car goes at the desired speed
and it simple open loop control is
correct there's no problem
okay now if there is a if there is
actually a
slope okay then you're going to get an
error right so if there's a slope of uh
of whatever the slope W there is going
to be you're going to be off as a result
of that and this is the the problem with
feed forward control that there will be
some unknown uh aspects of the
environment because of which you will
screw
Okay now what's the idea of Clos Loop
control Clos Loop control is that what
you do is you you look at your
speedometer by the right so you look at
the speedometer and you look at what is
your actual speed and then you have in
your mind the desired speed and you
measure the error okay so this is the
key concept of control there is a
desired speed there is the actual speed
you make a measurement you make a
measurement the difference is that's we
call the error now what do you do
basically what you want to do is to
drive the error to zero so it's really
the spirit of gradient descent you have
some error you want to drive it to zero
so what you will do is you will apply
some correction which is proportional to
the
error that has to be the spirit of it
apply some correction which is prop to
the
error okay so we we can work out the
math of
this so it's very important here that
you that you have a way of measuring the
output and you have your desired output
so the desired output is R the actual
output is y right so and the control is
so you've got this this block here it's
got this R and then there is this uh
essentially this differencing happening
here between R and Y because you have
the ability to measure the output okay
and then the control is so this R minus
y is an error right and what you do is
you say I don't like the error so I'm
going to apply a control and let's say I
do 10 10 times that that's the control I
apply okay and now uh we can write down
our equation so the F there is this
equation that we already had u minus5 w
this was in the
previous uh slide right that's the
that's the straightforward thing now in
this U there is the Y and then there is
a separate equation for y so I can plug
in uh so basically I can eliminate the
variables from this and I can eliminate
the U so y = 10 uus .5 W and this U is
10 r - 10 y -.5
w right so this is giving me 100 r - 100
y - 5
W okay and then I can take this 100 y
here and make it 101 y right with which
means y = 100 upon 101 r
- 5 upon
w okay so that's my uh so now I have 100
upon 101 is 99 5 upon 101 is
approximately 05 so the net equ the net
result is y = 0.99 r minus 0.05 W okay
so notice uh what's so cool about this
so what's the effect of the
disturbance the effect of the
disturbance previously was 5 W and now
it's become 0.005 W so the the effect of
the the road grade up slope down slope
is severely diminished it's been
diminished by
100x okay and you paid a little penalty
for it which is that the the Y is n9r so
you didn't get exactly your 55 m per
hour but 54.1 or 54.2 so you you lost a
little bit in this in the so Suppose
there was no grade right the road was
flat you would still pay that penalty so
you're you're so there is a steady state
error here you're not achieving y equals
R you're achieving 0 n hour but that's
like a small loss and the big thing is
you've got rid of the the consequence of
the disturbance which is w and the
disturbance has been diminished by a
factor of 100 this is the beauty of
control and did you need to know what is
the effect of the road no it's this is
your model free system to Kingdom Come
you know we talk about model free
reinforcement learning and modelbased
reinforcement learning this is totally
model free you do not need to know
anything about the system how well your
system works in practice will depend on
the model but all you did as an engineer
was to say measure the error and then
apply a correction which is proportional
to this
alosa the surface why what's the inition
why are you paying the penalty because
should always be zero no no because
essentially the correction here is based
on error right so you you have to have
an error in order to have a correction
otherwise you don't so there's a way to
fix
this no the error is not zero here with
the I mean in the with this algebra
right
so you want it ideally to be zero and
there is a way to achieve it and I'll
get to that okay no so that that's a
desirable point that you want it to be
zero and how do we achieve that I will
come to that but this simpleminded
scheme doesn't achieve it okay but it
this simpleminded scheme achieves the
goal of uh the the effect of the
disturbance is reduced by a fact of
100 and with and with nothing with no
knowledge really you do not need to know
much about any you do not need to know
about the noise you do not need to have
a you that like that the effect of the W
has to it can be unknown to you you
don't know how much it is you do not
need to know the grade you do not need
to know how much it messes up your
system all that is uh is it doesn't
matter right how effective it is depends
on that but you as a designer don't have
to do this you as a designer just had to
think of this number 10 I'm going to
take this error and then I'll repat 10
times of this yeah do the system still
assume that you're
using logic
aser no no I mean the logic is
everything is there on this slide
there's no feed forward here I mean
again we will come to fancier schemes
which have both a feed forward and a
feed back component and we want them for
any complicated scheme this is like the
most baby version and I wanted to do
this baby version because if you are a
computer scientist and have never taken
a controls class this is like your
introduction to control
yeah the T the flat ground concept that
do you still need it here because it
seems like with the air you should be
able to no you don't need to know about
it okay that's the point you don't need
to know about it because all you need to
know is there is an error the designer
of the control system needs to know
nothing about the system
this is the beauty it is totally model
free I mean it's like nothing all you
need to do is measure the error and then
just act on trying to reduce it it's
like the beauty of gradient descent it's
actually Ben re has a post on connecting
gradient descent and P ID control in
exactly this way okay now I'll do the
slightly fancier version Yeah
question sensing and the control on the
same space
yeah then you need to take a control
theory class so no so the point is in
the fancier versions we deal with all
that so so like yeah as I told you I'm
giving you the most basic version just
to give you an intuition okay uh okay
now what do people do in practice so
that what I described the the the the
next version of this is what's called a
PID controller so p p i d what do these
three letters stand for p is
proportional actually what we did so far
was a p controller because it was you
measure the error and the control is
proportional to the error so in this
case it was 10 times the error right so
that's it the proportion P is for
proportional to the error and then I is
the integral of the error so you compute
you can look at your past history and
you just observe the error and you keep
integrating that keep a su of the error
and that would deal with this problem of
the so-called stady State error because
if you were not going at the right speed
and you are slightly off this integral
term will keep accumulating and then to
drive that to zero you will do the right
thing then there is a term called D
which if I is integral then what should
D be derivative so the then you have a
derivative term and the idea there is
that if the derivative is positive and
high that means that the error is about
to increase even more which means you
better put in even more control that's
it so the idea of control is three
numbers okay the P term the I term and
the D term which are indicated by these
constants K sub p k sub i k
subd that you take a KP times the error
Ki * the integral of the error KD time
the derivative of the error and you feed
that in that's it and this is called a p
controller and the claim is that 95% of
controllers used in the real world IID
controllers so again uh my control
theory colleagues have to teach you for
one semester or two semesters but
actually I've just explained to you the
P ID controller in 10 minutes and and
this is what is what is used 95% this
95% number is probably made up but Ive
I've seen this from control theorists
yeah observing again why do we the
inte no well we we we we we we are
observing the error from the past so you
you use the history yeah so uh so this
is okay so now what could go wrong okay
let's think about what could go wrong
here what could go wrong so the natural
answer is just keep increasing the the
gain if you these Ks are sometimes
called gain so if you make the case
larger then the the the actually it does
a better job in terms of reducing the
error but no it doesn't go on forever
because at some point you get
instability so the control Loop uh you
you you you it things go
unstable and understanding that was
actually the beginnings of control
theory so the there was a lot of work on
these kinds of amplifiers and controls
uh done as by Babs in the 1920s and 30s
because there was a signal to be sent
across the continent for longdistance
phone calls and you needed to amplify it
but if you amplify too much then you get
into trouble I mean we see hear that all
the time when you have a speaker and you
you get that signal that's a that's a
example of this instability right so so
so there can be and and so the control
theory people essentially worry about
this so they they think about this
dynamical system and they want it to
converge to a point and not go off into
in crazy ways and and anyway that's a
lot of the seriousness is about that
this is model free control of course
control there are variations of control
there are model based control so if you
look at the the areas like Optimal
control those are model based so you
have some model of the Dynamics of the
system so something like uh X doal ax +
bu
U so here you know the A and B this is
the Dynamics of the system how it's
evolving and then somebody was asking me
about observation so the observation can
be something else why which is related
to the to the state of the system so X
here stands for state and U is the
control X and U are vectors A and B are
matrices and so on and this is the
linear version and then with this then
you can have a cost function which is
you want to have minimize error not use
up too much control energy and so on and
then then you can work out the math and
that's model based control so control
has both model based and model free
versions as we do in reinforcement
learning so reinforcement learning you
should think of as starting from this
base of control and then getting fancier
so the Marco decision processes were
defined in the late 50s by bman and uh
control theory had existed for 100 years
before that the is the first theoretical
paper on controls was written by James
Clark Maxwell Maxwell of Maxwell's
equations he wrote a paper on it in like
1870s and then in the 1920s and 30s
there was a lot of use of this for like
in electronics and so on so this is a
old vulnerable
field okay uh any questions
yeah KN the arm Dynamics there and the
ab and so here we we don't know the arm
Dynam Dynamics there is some unknown arm
Dynamics which so basically the
controller can operate without knowing
the arm Dynamics it it how effective it
is will depend on the arm
Dynamics I mean you so so what in fact
then there is a practical problem of how
do you tune these controls what how do
you set these right so they have to hack
around and they were in the old days
various heuristics for tuning this and
uh and I will tell you how we will deal
with it now because actually in
Practical robotic system now we still
have to deal with these controllers
because the lowest level controllers the
ones which control the motors at the
joints are actually P controllers so in
fact the setting of these constraints
can be done by a higher level so your
higher level reinforcement learning
algorithm can among its output produce
the the right choices of these constant
scale so that can be the out put of your
RL
policy okay so now a little bit to
connect uh just terminology so uh so
this is uh so the when you apply these
controllers you you it doesn't the error
doesn't immediately go to zero there is
some can be some overshoot and
undershoot and this is all standard
terminology from the control Community
there is this final error which is
called the steady state error and some
amount of time which is called all
settling time and if you do an
undergraduate class in control you'll
have to you know write homeworks on all
this stuff and I had to do this in
1978 okay this is but this is material
from like that nothing Chang this part
no the P control is still good I mean
your robot has them and and I mean I
studied it in 78 but but this was known
in the
1930s
right he this stuff this x do equals a x
this is around 1960 so this is very old
respectable field which people should
really know more about than they do okay
okay so now let's go to uh now go back
to robotics so with this little intro to
control let's go back to robotics so
this is uh how uh the block diagram is
for uh actual for a robot that we might
have in the lab
upstairs so uh so there is a desired
Behavior
controller uh so the controller uh then
the some amplifiers actuators and
transmission these might refer to some
electrical motors then these the motor
will produce a torque there's a dynamics
of the arm and environment then you
measure something it all seems
reasonable all these diagrams with boxes
and arrows you they they all kind kind
of make sense and and so does this one
okay uh
the uh the observation I would like to
make here is that uh Control Systems
often are
hierarchical and this is like a general
bit of thinking about planning and
control so suppose I'll use the most
cliched example I want to go from here
to Boston how am I going to do that so
there are there is a high level planning
stage that okay I go to SFO I take a
plane then I do something in Boston well
then how do I get to SFO well there is a
stage which requires taking an Uber then
before that there's a stage which
requires going from here to the front
door of the building before that there
is a stage where I'm actually moving all
the muscles of my legs right so control
in any complex problem has their
hierarchies which we have uh which are
important but it's a bit of a mystery as
to how to have them emerge automatically
most of the r literature tries to deal
with this but it's the solutions are
really not quite there usually the
solutions are designed I mean like I'm
I'm imposing this hierarchy here so
often in robot control this hierarchy is
imposed so the lowest level of the
hierarchy here is that there is my
electrical motor and I'm giving it some
signal in terms of current and then it
is moving and you have to uh and if it's
not doing moving at the right speed or
hasn't moved to the right position you
need to do something so that kind of a
that low-level controller is very
typically a PID
controller okay and then there is a
higher level controller which is
deciding what are the right joint angles
to to try to strive towards so that
lowlevel controller often has to work
very fast so it's like typically
operating at 1,00 Hertz whereas your
high level controller might be
you know some Transformer or neural
network which is operating at you know
20 HZ so different the lower level
controllers always much faster okay is
that does that make sense yeah and this
is uh so what we do is we often abstract
away the lower level stuff in the lower
level controller we just say okay we
trust the motor supplier or the robot
manufacturer and that the lowle
controllers would do sensible things
hopefully they give you access to it and
typically the way you want access is
because there'll be a low-level P ID
controller so you want to be able to
tweak the those K the case of P the case
of I case of D you need to be able to
tweak
those so far so
good okay now uh let's go back to
robotics uh and now I want to give you
uh some examples of uh of these just
some terminology here first motion
control Force control hybrid motion
Force control impedance control so let's
take examples so
uh so uh so uh these are all examples of
actions that we might want a robot to
perform and some of these involve motion
control some of them them involve Force
control some of them involve a mixture
of motion control and force control so
uh so let's consider let's say polishing
with a polishing wheel okay uh okay so
you're basically you're trying to remove
some material right so what's key is
that you have to apply Force it's
primarily about that Force right erasing
a white board I gave you that example so
you need so you need to be moving on the
surface of the board so therefore there
has to be motion if you don't move at
that mean there has to be motion and
then there has to be some lateral Force
applied right some tangential Force
spray painting this one you don't care
about forces it's all about movement
right and so on okay back massage
presumably this is you have to move
along the back of the person and you
have to apply a force so it's hybrid so
uh
anyway the main value here is to say
that different tasks that we have uh for
robots to do they will involve a
combination of
movement how the end affector moves and
uh forces to be applied to and and this
is more or less trivial right because if
you want to change the environment you
have to apply forces that is the only
way to change the world that's what
Newton told us right
okay okay so now I'm going to go through
another little bit of uh uh Cartoon math
basically so I'm going to now take uh
take like some the simple uh joint here
so this is like a revolute joint it has
mass m and it is at angle Theta and I'm
trying to rotate it from one position to
another and now let's try to design a
control law to achieve some some desired
rotation so uh what does the math say so
in this case the equation for the
Dynamics it it follows that same pattern
that we did earlier in the lecture it's
that same pattern with those different
terms corresponding to the mass term the
velocity terms the gravity term but the
con huh yeah because it's super simple
yeah yeah yeah yeah so here we have
essentially the torque is super simple
it's like there is a a gravity term
there's a viscosity term there's a
there's a mass acceleration term anyway
again the details do not matter
you should just know that somebody can
work all this out because we are living
200 years after Newton and legran okay
so okay so the you and you what you want
to do is now let's put in the control
theory uh stuff here so the torque is
going to be given by this P ID
controller so the PID controller we have
to have this Theta sub e Theta sub means
that you have to have some measurement
of the error and measurement of the
error is typically possible in a robot
because all the joints you have these
motors and there are encoders on those
Motors so that you know the angle that
it is at 87° or 105° so that information
is given to you by the encoders on the
motors so so we have so from that we can
compute this Theta sa which is the
difference between the desired angle and
the actual angle is it reliable enough
in practice
Yeah so this is
uh and of course this is for one joint
so I'm doing the baby case when you have
many joints you just do this separately
for every joint so it's pretty done in a
straightforward way okay and uh so what
this says is so again you can do
simple-minded stuff suppose you did not
have the integral term and you just had
a proportional control or so there are
variations we call this there's a p ID
controller you can have a PD controller
PD contr controller means that you don't
have the I term you can have a p
controller which means you don't have
either the I or D term right you can
have a pi controller which is you just
have a proportional and integral term so
all these variations are possible so if
you do a simpleminded version you will
have a situation quite similar to that
cruise control on the car you'll get a
little steady state error because you
didn't put an integral
ter uh okay and uh this is uh you're not
supposed to really read it in detail but
one can do the algebra and I mean people
can do this stuff right so uh okay I'll
skip this but uh okay and then there is
a version of this which is what
about uh tracking a trajectory okay so
there's a there's a terminology here
there's set point control set point
means that I for example it could be
that in this this uh this little uh one
arm uh uh robot I wanted it to go from
being at uh you know uh uh like at minus
piun by2 to0 so I it was going to be to
go down and I wanted to raise it to
horizontal right that's an example so
that set point control meaning that you
want to be in one place and you specify
that and you want to stabilize there so
uh so there you are uh and often you
shift the origin to be zero uh at that
place and the goal is to just keep keep
stay there not change okay then there
can be trajectory control so in
trajectories you want to go you want to
move your Theta should change as a
function of time in a certain way you
want to achieve that but we have a
physical system that means that it
cannot magically change from a Theta of
90° to at the next moment being 0
degrees I mean the laws of physics apply
so the Dynamics of the system controls
how you and evolve the system so you
have to do apply your control law
cognizant of the fa fact that the these
are physical objects which have to
follow Newtonian Dynamics and we can
write down the equations for that so
this creates there this whole game of
trajectory optimization and so on and
designing control laws for that again
this kept our colleagues occupied in the
past and back in the 80s and ' 90s all
these things were worked out so it's all
there you should read up about it
okay and uh I am uh going to uh okay I
should give you a break at some point
but uh uh there is
a I'm not really going to go into this
so so you
you okay I I I want to give a little
flavor of it which is that uh
essentially this class of controllers
which are called computed torque control
or uh feedback linearization again this
is this is a topic which I'm really not
going to explain but uh the idea is that
you actually do a combination of the
using the model the feed forward term so
let us assume that we know the Dynamics
so we knowing the Dynamics means that
you know the mass of the link and things
like that right so for your known robot
you know the you know the the the masses
of the links it's all there in the urdf
file and you incorporate that so you
don't assume that it's like a all that
is an unknown and yet and you also have
a term which is measuring the error and
feeding it back using the PID control so
you design a controller which has both
of these
aspects and if you want you can think of
it as a combination of a feed forward
and a feedback controller the feed for
covered part deals with the known
Dynamics corresponding to the uh the
masses of the links and so on and then
there is always going to be unmodeled
Dynamics and and
disturbances and your uh feedback loop
is taken care of that and uh so this is
a very good design principle and and
that's what uh what this uh computer
talk control is sort of a way of of
dealing with this properly okay and
there are variations on this theme so
I'm not going to go there and this
picture tries to give you examples so
here the goal was so there is this bar
linkage which you which was at 45
degrees and you want it to go to 135
Dees and there is a desired
trajectory and there is a
simple uh uh you know so over time the
the you know it does the right thing but
if there are errors then the the
computer talk controller does better so
there are three controllers here there's
the FF which is a feedforward controller
which doesn't have any mechanism for
dealing with disturbances it just you
just assume that everything is correct
you do that so that's like my first
example for driving a car on the road
you just pick pick uh you you have this
you you pick a certain throttle angle
and that's it so that's the pure Fe Fe
forward FF is for Pure feed forward then
you can design a controller which is
based on just error measurement and
doing the right thing so that's the PID
controller and then there is this
computed torque controller which is a
combination you you you build in your
prior knowledge if you will okay that's
in the feed forward part and yet you
also measure the error and you correct
on that and uh the purpose of these two
panels is to show that that works the
best
and that's not surprising I mean it's
intuitive that if you have prior
knowledge it should
help uh okay uh and at this point I'll
give you a break so let's take a
10-minute break and resume at 4:5